momendeavors.com 2015-04-25

# Privacy Policy & Disclosure

Welcome to Mom Endeavors!

Mom Endeavors  has created this Privacy Policy in order to set forth the principles governing our information-gathering and dissemination practices, including but not limited to such activities as forums, chat rooms, personal profile pages, product reviews, article commentary, blogs, RSS feeds and newsletters, among other offerings. Mom Endeavors has a strong commitment to the privacy of our users. Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through MomEndeavors.com and not to information collected offline or to information you may provide to any third-party sites to which Mom Endeavors may link, except as expressly provided herein.

**Information We Collect**

There are two kinds of information that #NAME# can obtain about you: “Anonymous Information” and “Personally Identifiable Information.” “Anonymous Information” consists of non-personally-identifiable data, such as your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address or domain, or information about your usage on Mom Endeavors that is used for administrative purposes only. For example, an IP address is a unique string of numbers that is assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. Web servers automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We may collect our users’ IP addresses for such purposes as to help diagnose problems with our servers and to report aggregate information to our advertisers, corporate affiliates and consultants, and to third parties that perform particular services on our behalf. We may also use the information linked to IP addresses to ban users who violate our Terms and Conditions of use. “Personally Identifiable Information” is any information that personally identifies you, such as your name, street address, email address, or telephone number. We collect such information when, for example, you enter a contest, subscribe to our email newsletter, and participate in other interactive online activities such as forums. When we collect Personally Identifiable Information from you, you will have the opportunity to “opt in” to receive email or other digital communications from us and/or our business partners. If you have submitted your personal information to #NAME#, you may correct, amend or delete the Personally Identifiable Information maintained on file about you if it is incorrect. In all cases, we will only use your information as permitted by law. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Privacy Policy, however, we may disclose Personally Identifiable Information to others if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law or with legal process; (b) protect and defend our rights and property; (c) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Site; or (d) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public. Please note that we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases.

**Use of “Cookies”**

Mom Endeavors uses “cookies” – data that is transferred from MomEndeavors.com to your hard drive for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit Mom Endeavors. Some of the advertisements appearing on MomEndeavors.com are delivered by our third-party ad network, DoubleClick. In the course of serving advertisements, DoubleClick may place or recognize a unique “cookie” in your browser’s cache, and may use Anonymous Information (including date/time of the banner ad displayed, the ad that was displayed and the IP address of the visitor) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you and to collect statistical information. For more information about DoubleClick’s privacy policy, [please click here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/). If you would like to “opt out” of having a unique cookie placed on your hard drive by DoubleClick, [please click here](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?hl=en=#display_optout) or [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). Gourmet Ads primary ad server is Appnexus and you can [opt out of cookies here](http://appnexus.com/platform-policy#choices) from them. You can also opt out of cookies using the Network Advertising Initiative [opt-out page here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

**Disclosure of Information through Business Transfers**

As we continue to develop our business, we may buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses, and in so doing, acquire customer information. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. Similarly, in the event that a portion or all of Mom Endeavors’ assets are sold or transferred to a third party, customer information (including your email address) would likely be one of the transferred business assets.

**Third Party Web Sites**

MomEndeavors.com contains links to third-party Web sites not owned or controlled by Mom Endeavors. Mom Endeavors is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third-party Web sites. Inclusion of any linked Web site on Mom Endeavors does not imply or express an approval or endorsement of the linked Web site by us, or of any of the content, opinions, products or services provided on these Web sites. Even if an affiliation exists between Mom Endeavors and a third-party Web site, we exercise no control over linked sites. Each of these linked sites maintains its own independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures. If you visit a Web site via a link from one of our Sites, we encourage you to consult that Web site’s privacy policy before providing any personal information, and whenever interacting with any such Web site.

**Public Forums**

Mom Endeavors may make chat rooms, forums, blogs, article commenting, and personal profile pages available to users. Please remember that any such information that you may choose to provide in these areas becomes accessible to the public, and also becomes the property of Mom Endeavors in accordance with our Terms and Conditions, and we may use such information in any way that we see fit. Consequently, you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information or to upload material of any kind.

**Security**

Mom Endeavors has reasonable security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Security of information communicated by or to us over the Internet is of utmost concern to us; however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that your email, like most, if not all, unencrypted Internet communications, may potentially be accessed and viewed by other Internet users, without your knowledge and permission, while in transit to us. For that reason, to protect your privacy, please do not use email to communicate information to us that you consider confidential. While we strive to protect your personal information, Mom Endeavors cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. Once we receive your transmission, we will use reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our internal systems. Depending on the nature of the inquiry, your communication may be discarded or archived.

**Policy Regarding Minors**

Children should always ask parents before providing any personal information online. No information should be submitted to or posted on Mom Endeavors by any minor (a person under 18 years of age) without the consent of a parent or guardian. Unless otherwise disclosed during collection, we do not knowingly provide any Personally Identifiable Information about minors, regardless of its source, nor is this information knowingly used by Mom Endeavors for any marketing or promotional purposes. Minors are not eligible to participate in contests. Mom Endeavors abides by the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act. In the event that we learn that we have collected information from any child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete this information from our database as quickly as reasonably possible. If you believe that any Site has collected any information about anyone under 13, please contact Mom Endeavors’ Site Administrator via postal mail or email at one of the addresses listed below.

**Financial Relationships**

Please note that Mom Endeavors may have financial relationships with some of the merchants/vendors mentioned on this website. In some instances, Mom Endeavors may be compensated if consumers choose to utilize the links located throughout the content on this site and generate sales for said merchant/vendor.

**Limitation of Liability**

MOM ENDEAVORS PROVIDES THE INFORMATION, SERVICES AND PRODUCTS ON THIS WEB SITES “AS IS” WITHOUT WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND. YOU AGREE THAT MOM ENDEAVORS SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY CONTENT FOUND ON OUR FORUMS THATANY DOWNLOADING OF MATERIALS FOUND ON OR THROUGH MOM ENDEAVORS FORUMS IS DONE AT YOUR OWN RISK, AND THAT MOM ENDEAVORS IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR UNSOLICITED COMMUNICATIONS THAT ARISE FROM YOUR POSTINGS. MOM ENDEAVORS SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE IN ANY MANNER FOR THE ACTS OF ANY THIRD PARTY, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION, ANY THIRD PARTY AD NETWORK.

**Consent and Modifications to this Privacy Statement**

MomEndeavors.com is controlled, operated and administered entirely within the United States. By using Mom Endeavors and/or participating in the activities of the Mom Endeavors Community, you signify your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree with this Privacy Statement, please do not disclose any personal information through our site. Mom Endeavors may modify this Privacy Statement at any time, at its discretion, and modifications are effective upon being posted on this the applicable Site. You are responsible for reviewing this Privacy Statement periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes to it.

_This Privacy Policy is effective as of December 2013 and supersedes all earlier versions of our Privacy Policy.  _

**Disclosure**

_Mom Endeavors_ is written and edited by me, Sara W. This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, products for review and other forms of compensation.  For questions about this blog, please send an email to momendeavors (at) gmail (dot) com.

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards.  I believe in honesty of relationship, opinion, and identity. I sometimes have the opportunity to accept forms of cash advertising, sponsorships, paid insertions, and other forms of compensation. Any content, advertising space, or post as such will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content. I may also receive compensation for opinions/reviews on products, services, websites, or other various topics.  However, I always give my honest opinion, findings, beliefs, and/or experience.  Whether compensated or not, I only endorse products or services that I believe, based on my experience, warrant such an endorsement.  Because the content written here is my own opinion, any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer or provider.

[Mom Endeavors.com](http://www.momendeavors.com/) does contain affiliate links.  If a reader clicks through such a link on this blog and makes a purchase/signs up for that service, I receive a small compensation.  I choose my affiliates carefully to bring my readers special deals and/or share about products I like. As affiliates are third-parties, I am not responsible for their acts or omissions.  Please contact the third-party affiliate directly, if you have

questions about the products are services they offer.  
_Valid from November 16, 2010_
